Support Admin Watch on kissasia.cam or kisskh.org
دعم المشرف شاهد على kissasia.cam أو kisskh.org
[Lin's Mansion]
[قصر لين]
Looks like I overthought it.
يبدو أنني فكرت في الأمر أكثر من اللازم.
[Six days ago] I thought it was a trap,
[منذ ستة أيام] اعتقدت أنه فخ،
but I didn't
ولكنني لم افعل
realize it was you.
أدركت أنه أنت.
You...
أنت...
You harassed my sister...
لقد ضايقت أختي...
Chairman.
رئيس مجلس الإدارة.
It is...
إنها...
It's nothing.
لا شئ.
Don't mind him.
لا تهتم به.
Go after him.
إذهب خلفه.
Chairman.
رئيس مجلس الإدارة.
[Treasure at Dawn] ♪Reach the highest level♪
[كنز عند الفجر] ♪الوصول إلى أعلى مستوى♪
♪Reach the state of no desire, illuminate the virtuous light♪
♪الوصول إلى حالة عدم الرغبة، وإضاءة النور الفاضل♪
♪Man is upright because he is moral, and he is strong because he is upright♪
♪الإنسان مستقيم لأنه أخلاقي، وهو قوي لأنه مستقيم♪
♪Upright, strong, and fair♪
♪ مستقيم، قوي، وعادل♪
♪I am the fire♪
♪أنا النار♪
♪Burning out all desires♪
♪حرق كل الرغبات♪
♪River can't put me out♪
♪النهر لا يستطيع إخراجي♪
♪Yang's beginning leads to development. Wu Chi creates Tai Chi♪
♪بداية يانغ تُفضي إلى التطور. وو تشي يُبدع تاي تشي♪
♪People mistake their bodily form, forgetting the true mind within♪
♪يخطئ الناس في فهم شكل أجسادهم، وينسون العقل الحقيقي في داخلهم♪
♪People make their own enemies♪
♪الناس يصنعون أعداءهم♪
♪Books are all about reason. People are full of purpose♪
الكتب كلها تدور حول المنطق. الناس مليئون بالهدف.
♪People are overrun by illusions♪
♪الناس غارقون في الأوهام♪
♪They are fascinated by illusions♪
♪إنهم مفتونون بالأوهام♪
♪With a pure mind, sitting in the clouds♪
♪مع عقل نقي، جالسًا في السحاب♪
♪Watching people creating dreams♪
♪مشاهدة الناس وهم يصنعون الأحلام♪
♪Is it painful to live in the world?♪
♪هل العيش في العالم مؤلم؟♪
♪Learn from nature. Forget all your desires♪
♪تعلم من الطبيعة. انسَ كل رغباتك♪
♪How about clearing all my thoughts?♪
♪ماذا عن تصفية كل أفكاري؟♪
♪Moths fly into the fire♪
♪العث يطير في النار♪
♪The fire melts old shackles♪
♪النار تذيب القيود القديمة♪
♪Today, I know it's me♪
♪اليوم، أعلم أنه أنا♪
[Treasure at Dawn]
[كنز عند الفجر]
[Episode 11] [Recalling Old Affairs, Siming Courts Death]
[الحلقة 11] [استرجاع الشؤون القديمة، سيمينغ يتودد إلى الموت]
Chairman.
رئيس مجلس الإدارة.
Why are you so flustered?
لماذا أنت مرتبك هكذا؟
The Breakwall traitor was caught
تم القبض على خائن بريك وول
by those two brats.
من قبل هذين الطفلين.
Good.
جيد.
Those two baiters
هذين الطُعمين
finally helped us catch the big fish.
لقد ساعدنا أخيرا في صيد السمكة الكبيرة.
Yes, sir.
نعم سيدي.
Chairman, you're brilliant.
السيد الرئيس، أنت رائع.
The sudden appearance
الظهور المفاجئ
of those two almost disrupted
من بين هذين الاثنين تم تعطيلهما تقريبًا
your original plan.
خطتك الأصلية.
I don't think the Breakwall traitors
لا أعتقد أن الخونة هم من بريكوال
would have shown up so soon
لقد كان سيظهر قريبا جدا
if you hadn't gotten
لو لم تحصل
Lord's Mansion involved.
قصر اللورد متورط.
Chairman.
رئيس مجلس الإدارة.
There is one thing I don't understand.
هناك شيء واحد لا أفهمه.
At what point did you decide
في أي نقطة قررت؟
to start using these two?
للبدء باستخدام هذين الاثنين؟
From the day they were captured
منذ اليوم الذي تم القبض عليهم فيه
by the Chamber of Commerce and were to be executed.
من قبل غرفة التجارة وكان من المقرر تنفيذه.
Who saved them?
من أنقذهم؟
Wen Jiu.
ون جيو.
No.
لا.
It was
لقد كان
Wen Yu.
ون يو.
That's right.
هذا صحيح.
I didn't expect these two outsiders
لم أتوقع هذين الغريبين
to be so close to Lord Wen,
أن أكون قريبًا جدًا من اللورد وين،
so I followed their plot
لذلك تابعت مؤامرتهم
and used them to get Lord Wen involved
واستخدموها لإشراك اللورد وين
and make things worse.
وتجعل الأمور أسوأ.
That way,
بهذه الطريقة،
Lin's Mansion would be turned upside down.
سيتم قلب قصر لين رأسًا على عقب.
It was only a matter of time
لقد كانت مسألة وقت فقط
before the traitor was forced out.
قبل أن يتم إخراج الخائن.
Brilliant.
باهِر.
That day, after Song Jingye's death,
في ذلك اليوم، بعد وفاة سونغ جينغي،
I didn't find the Cloud-shaped Jade.
لم أجد اليشم على شكل سحابة.
That Breakwall traitor
هذا الخائن بريكوال
must have taken
يجب أن يكون قد اتخذ
the Cloud-shaped Jade away before me.
سحابة اليشم على شكل بعيدا أمامي.
Now, Fu Sheng has forced out this Breakwall traitor,
الآن، أجبر فو شنغ هذا الخائن على الخروج،
so you can finish it.
حتى تتمكن من الانتهاء منه.
Catch the traitor, take back the Cloud-shaped Jade,
قبض على الخائن، واسترجع اليشم على شكل سحابة،
and then get rid of the two decoys.
ومن ثم تخلص من الطُعمين.
After working for me for so long,
بعد العمل معي لفترة طويلة،
you've finally grown up a bit.
لقد كبرت أخيرا قليلا.
Thank you.
شكرًا لك.
All thanks to your exceptional brilliance, Chairman.
كل الشكر لذكائك الاستثنائي، السيد الرئيس.
Your plan to kill three birds
خطتك لقتل ثلاثة طيور
with one stone was well-thought-out
بحجر واحد كان مدروسا جيدا
and truly formidable.
وهي هائلة حقا.
Chairman.
رئيس مجلس الإدارة.
Now we should...
الآن ينبغي علينا...
We've waited so long.
لقد انتظرنا لفترة طويلة.
Now that the fish is hooked,
الآن بعد أن تم اصطياد السمكة،
it's time to catch it.
حان الوقت للإمساك به.
Senior.
كبير.
[Fair and Square]
[عادل ومربع]
You've been holding out on me.
لقد كنت تتمسك بي.
All these years,
كل هذه السنوات،
I thought you were dead.
اعتقدت أنك ميت.
You've found me,
لقد وجدتني
so I'm afraid
لذلك أنا خائف
the sages already know.
والحكماء يعرفون ذلك بالفعل.
Do it.
افعلها.
Senior.
كبير.
You've grown old.
لقد كبرت.
I remember
انا اتذكر
when I first met you,
عندما التقيت بك لأول مرة،
you were just a little girl
لقد كنت مجرد فتاة صغيرة
of three or four.
من ثلاثة أو أربعة.
When you saw me,
عندما رأيتني،
you followed me around
لقد اتبعتني
and yelled,
وصرخت
"Play with me, okay?"
" العب معي ، حسنًا؟"
Senior.
كبير.
Why did you defect back then?
لماذا انشققت حينها؟
Because I was afraid of death.
لأني كنت خائفة من الموت.
Yunting.
يونتينج.
I'm not the Senior
أنا لست كبير السن
you knew back then.
لقد عرفت ذلك في ذلك الوقت.
Do you still have the gauze scarf
هل لا يزال لديك وشاح الشاش؟
I gave you?
هل أعطيتك؟
You grew up
لقد كبرت
with me.
معي.
You're the only family member
أنت العضو الوحيد في العائلة
in this world
في هذا العالم
that I'm attached to.
الذي أنا مرتبط به.
How could I throw away
كيف يمكنني التخلص منها
the gift you gave me?
الهدية التي قدمتها لي؟
Okay.
تمام.
We've already caught up.
لقد وصلنا بالفعل إلى الهدف.
Do it.
افعلها.
Since we're family,
بما أننا عائلة،
how could I do that?
كيف يمكنني أن أفعل ذلك؟
Then what will you tell them
ثم ماذا ستقول لهم
when you get back?
عندما تعود؟
The situation is different.
الوضع مختلف .
The clue to the Treasure of the Sealed Book has reappeared,
لقد ظهر دليل كنز الكتاب المختوم مرة أخرى،
so the sages need to hear from you.
لذلك فإن الحكماء بحاجة إلى سماع رأيك.
Later,
لاحقاً،
kill those three behind you
اقتل هؤلاء الثلاثة خلفك
and destroy their bodies.
وتدمير أجسادهم.
Then, return to Breakwall
ثم العودة إلى Breakwall
with the help of Li Zhizhuo.
بمساعدة لي تشيزوو.
At that time,
في ذلك الوقت،
we will be able to see
سوف نكون قادرين على الرؤية
each other often again.
بعضنا البعض في كثير من الأحيان مرة أخرى.
Senior.
كبير.
Use this to find me.
استخدم هذا للعثور علي.
Li Zhizhuo will be arriving soon,
لي تشيزوو سيصل قريبا،
so I'll have to duck
لذلك سأضطر إلى الانحناء
and leave.
و أرحل.
Don't worry.
لا تقلق.
I'll do it.
سأفعل ذلك.
She loves cleanliness.
إنها تحب النظافة.
She'll be pissed
سوف تكون غاضبة
if she knows it's dirty.
إذا كانت تعلم أنها قذرة.
Search the place.
ابحث عن المكان.
Chairman.
رئيس مجلس الإدارة.
The murderer is here
القاتل هنا
and has been executed.
وقد تم تنفيذ الحكم فيه.
Did you kill him?
هل قتلته؟
Luckily, you arrived in time.
لحسن الحظ، لقد وصلت في الوقت المناسب.
This guy knew
هذا الرجل عرف
he wouldn't get away with it
لن يفلت من العقاب
and panicked,
وذعرت
so I got him.
لذلك حصلت عليه.
You did well
لقد فعلت جيدا
this time.
هذه المرة.
Stop it.
اوقفها.
Come on.
تعال.
Young Mistress,
سيدتي الشابة،
you're finally here.
أنت هنا أخيرا.
Fu Sheng
فو شنغ
is injured.
مصاب.
I don't know how badly he's hurt.
لا أعلم مدى خطورة إصابته.
Young Mistress.
سيدة شابة.
Take them back
استرجعهم
before we delay treatment.
قبل أن نؤجل العلاج.
Jiu, take them away.
جيو، خذهم بعيدًا.
You, come with us.
أنت، تعال معنا.
Come on.
تعال.
See you.
أرك لاحقًا.
Take this traitor back
خذ هذا الخائن مرة أخرى
and burn the house down.
وأحرق البيت.
Yes, sir.
نعم سيدي.
[Fair and Square]
[عادل ومربع]
Let's go.
دعنا نذهب.
[Qinya House]
[بيت كينيا]
I found this
لقد وجدت هذا
where Song Jingye died.
حيث توفي سونغ جينغي.
I wanted
انا اردت
to give it to Her Excellency.
لتسليمها لصاحبة السعادة.
I don't know
لا أعرف
if she will spare my life.
إذا كانت ستبقي على حياتي.
We'll help you.
سنقوم بمساعدتك.
That's enough, don't shout.
كفى، لا تصرخ.
Does it hurt so much
هل يؤلمني كثيرا؟
for such a small wound?
لمثل هذا الجرح الصغير؟
How can it not hurt?
كيف لا يؤلم؟
I'm going to die.
انا سأموت.
It's not his fault.
إنه ليس خطؤه.
I gave him medicine to enhance his five senses.
لقد أعطيته دواءً لتقوية حواسه الخمس.
Fu Sheng, you're awake.
فو شنغ، أنت مستيقظ.
Is this what you call unstable?
هل هذا ما تسميه غير مستقر؟
This elevates the five senses,
وهذا يرفع الحواس الخمس،
so the pain will be elevated as well.
لذلك سوف يرتفع الألم أيضًا.
So when will the effect be gone?
فمتى سيختفي التأثير؟
I don't know.
لا أعرف.
It's my first time using it too.
إنها المرة الأولى التي أستخدمه فيها أيضًا.
I seem to owe you in my past life.
يبدو أنني مدين لك في حياتي الماضية.
If I had known,
لو كنت أعلم،
I would have stayed in Shangyi and been executed.
كنت سأبقى في شانغهاي وأُعدم.
I'm sorry.
أنا آسف.
Fu Sheng.
فو شنغ.
I suffered this for you,
لقد عانيت من هذا من أجلك،
so think about how to compensate me.
لذلك فكر في كيفية تعويضي.
Then
ثم
let's write it down.
دعونا نكتبها.
You...
أنت...
Enough. Stop this show.
كفى. أوقفوا هذا العرض.
Do you know
هل تعلم
how dangerous it was yesterday?
كم كان الأمر خطيرًا بالأمس؟
If I hadn't gotten there in time,
لو لم أصل هناك في الوقت المناسب،
you two would have been buried today.
لقد تم دفنكما اليوم.
What about
ماذا عن
Master Lin and Sun Siming?
المعلم لين وسون سيمينغ؟
Sun Siming is still alive,
سون سيمينغ لا يزال على قيد الحياة،
but
لكن
Master Lin is dead.
لقد مات السيد لين.
Who killed him?
من قتله؟
I don't know.
لا أعرف.
I was afraid that the Jibei Chamber of Commerce
كنت خائفة من أن غرفة تجارة جيبي
would take revenge on you,
سوف ينتقم منك
so I didn't care about anything else.
لذلك لم أهتم بأي شيء آخر.
I asked Jiu
سألت جيو
to bring you back.
لإعادتك.
I really don't know
انا حقا لا اعرف
what happened after that,
ماذا حدث بعد ذلك؟
but
لكن
Lin's Mansion was set on fire
تم إشعال النار في قصر لين
by the Jibei Chamber of Commerce.
من قبل غرفة تجارة جيبي.
On fire?
لا يمكن إيقافه؟
Did you see a woman
هل رأيت امرأة
in black?
باللون الأسود؟
Were there other women with you?
هل كان هناك نساء أخريات معك؟
Who was she?
من كانت هي؟
I'd like to know who she was too.
وأريد أن أعرف من هي أيضًا.
OK.
نعم.
By the way, this is the third time
بالمناسبة، هذه هي المرة الثالثة
I've saved you.
لقد انقذتك.
Tell me.
أخبرني.
How do you plan to repay me?
كيف تخطط لسداد لي؟
I wanted to thank you for saving my life,
أردت أن أشكرك على إنقاذ حياتي،
but I thought I couldn't repay you with thanks,
ولكنني اعتقدت أنني لا أستطيع أن أرد لك الشكر،
so I promised to work for you
لذا وعدت بالعمل معك
forever in my next life.
إلى الأبد في حياتي القادمة.
Don't say these meaningless ones.
لا تقل هذه الكلمات التي لا معنى لها.
I don't care about your labor.
لا يهمني عملك.
Wen Jue.
ون جوي.
No matter what,
مهما كان الأمر،
I really don't know how to repay
أنا حقا لا أعرف كيفية سداد
being saved by you so many times,
لقد تم إنقاذي من قبلك عدة مرات،
so I only have to do my best
لذلك كل ما علي فعله هو أن أبذل قصارى جهدي
to save Lord Wen
لإنقاذ اللورد وين
in order to live up to your saving grace these three times.
لكي تعيش وفقًا لنعمتك الخلاصية هذه المرات الثلاث.
That's what you said.
هذا ما قلته.
If you can cure my father,
إذا كنت تستطيع علاج والدي،
the favor of saving your life
نعمة إنقاذ حياتك
will be written off.
سيتم شطبها.
I'll open a medical center for you
سأفتح لك مركز طبي
in Xichuan, okay?
في شيتشوان، حسنًا؟
That would be great.
سيكون ذلك رائعا.
But I need to warn you
ولكنني أريد أن أحذرك
that if you can't cure him,
أنه إذا لم تتمكن من علاجه،
you two will pay back everything
سوف تسددون كل شيء
I've given you.
لقد أعطيتك.
Why is it that if he can cure your father,
لماذا إذا كان بإمكانه علاج والدك،
you're only giving him a clinic
أنت فقط تعطيه عيادة
while asking us both to pay back if he can't?
بينما يطلب منا كلينا أن نسدد إذا لم يستطع؟
I don't care.
لا أهتم.
I must have my share in the clinic.
يجب أن يكون لي نصيب في العيادة.
Young Mistress.
سيدة شابة.
The city lord wants to see you.
يريد سيد المدينة رؤيتك.
Jiu,
جيو،
can't you see
ألا تستطيع أن ترى؟
I have a patient here?
هل لدي مريض هنا؟
My leg.
ساقي.
- My leg hurts. - I'll bandage it.
- ساقي تؤلمني. - سأضمدها.
I'll bandage it.
سأضمده.
Come on.
تعال.
Be careful.
احرص.
- I'm hurt bad this time. - Look.
- لقد أصبت بجروح بالغة هذه المرة. - انظر.
I'm sure that their condition
أنا متأكد من أن حالتهم
is not bothering you.
لا يزعجك.
Jiu, you're right.
جيو، أنت على حق.
My father must want to see me
لابد أن والدي يريد رؤيتي
because he has something big to discuss.
لأنه لديه شيء كبير لمناقشته.
I can't keep my dad waiting.
لا أستطيع أن أجعل والدي ينتظر.
So,
لذا،
you guys,
يا رفاق،
take care of it yourself.
اعتني بها بنفسك.
Such a big Xichuan
مثل هذا Xichuan كبير
cannot do anything without me.
لا أستطيع فعل أي شيء بدوني.
Jiu.
جيو.
Can you not embarrass me
هل يمكنك أن لا تحرجني؟
in front of my friends?
أمام أصدقائي؟
My nephew.
ابن أخي.
Have you come today
هل أتيت اليوم
with many possessions
مع العديد من الممتلكات
because you have something to say to me?
لأن لديك شيئا لتقوله لي؟
Lord Wen.
اللورد وين.
I'm a rough man who doesn't know how to talk.
أنا رجل قاسي لا يعرف كيف يتحدث.
I have come today
لقد جئت اليوم
to offer a bride price.
لتقديم مهر العروس.
I have admired Young Mistress for a long time,
لقد كنت معجبًا بـ Young Mistress منذ فترة طويلة،
so please
لذا من فضلك
fulfill us.
إشبعنا.
Okay.
تمام.
What is OK?
ما هو جيد؟
Come on.
تعال.
Young Mistress.
سيدة شابة.
Take your things and disappear.
خذ أغراضك و إختفي.
I don't want to see you.
لا أريد رؤيتك.
Don't take it personally.
لا تأخذ الأمر على محمل شخصي.
Jue.
نعم.
Young Mistress.
سيدة شابة.
If you don't like these,
إذا كنت لا تحب هذه،
what do you like?
ماذا تريد؟
I'll get them for you at once.
سأحضرها لك على الفور.
I like you to stay away from me.
أحب أن تبتعد عني.
Listen.
يستمع.
If you ever come to propose again,
إذا أتيت مرة أخرى لتقدم عرض الزواج،
I'll ask Jiu to throw you out.
سأطلب من جيو أن يطردك.
Don't take it personally.
لا تأخذ الأمر على محمل شخصي.
Lord Wen.
اللورد وين.
Sooner or later, we'll all be family.
عاجلاً أم آجلاً، سوف نصبح جميعاً عائلة.
Goodbye.
مع السلامة.
Who's your family?
من هي عائلتك؟
Jue.
نعم.
Be well.
كن بخير.
Dad.
أب.
[Firm as a Rock]
[ثابت كالصخر]
You sold me out
لقد بعتني
for these things?
لهذه الأشياء؟
You are the most precious thing I have.
أنت أغلى ما أملك.
How can these things
كيف يمكن لهذه الأشياء
compare to you?
مقارنة بك؟
So you're just tired of me
إذن أنت تعبت مني
and want to get rid of me?
وتريد أن تتخلص مني؟
I'm not.
انا لست كذلك.
Jue.
نعم.
You have to realize
عليك أن تدرك
that I'm doing this
أنني أفعل هذا
so that you can have a firm foothold
حتى تتمكن من الحصول على موطئ قدم ثابت
in Xichuan in the future.
في شيتشوان في المستقبل.
Can I, the Young Mistress of Xichuan,
هل يمكنني، السيدة الشابة من شيتشوان،
be messed with by any fool?
هل يمكن أن يتلاعب به أي أحمق؟
I know.
أنا أعرف.
You just love Xubu Huai
أنت فقط تحب Xubu Huai
and want him to be your son.
وتريده أن يكون ابنك.
I don't.
أنا لا.
I have to tell you.
يجب أن أخبرك.
I'll die before I marry him.
سأموت قبل أن أتزوجه.
Jue.
نعم.
Dad.
أب.
- Sir. - Dad.
- سيدي - أبي.
Sir.
سيد.
Come on.
تعال.
Fu Sheng.
فو شنغ.
How is my father doing?
كيف حال والدي؟
Wasn't he cured last time?
ألم يتم شفاؤه في المرة الماضية؟
Why did he faint?
لماذا أغمي عليه؟
Lord Wen is nothing serious.
اللورد وين ليس شيئا خطيرا.
Just heatstroke.
مجرد ضربة شمس.
- Heatstroke? - I'll give him some medicine
- ضربة شمس؟ - سأعطيه بعض الدواء
to relieve heatstroke,
لتخفيف ضربة الشمس،
and he'll be fine.
وسيكون بخير.
Jue.
نعم.
Physician Fu is here, don't worry,
الطبيب فو هنا، لا تقلق،
but I woke up
ولكنني استيقظت
feeling hungry.
أشعر بالجوع.
Go see if there's
اذهب وانظر إذا كان هناك
any lotus seed congee in the kitchen.
أي عصيدة بذور اللوتس الموجودة في المطبخ.
Okay.
تمام.
I'll be right there.
سأكون هناك حالا.
Fu Sheng.
فو شنغ.
Come out for a moment.
اخرج للحظة واحدة.
I want to talk to you.
أريد أن أتحدث معك.
Fu Sheng.
فو شنغ.
Do you know
هل تعلم
why my father suddenly fainted?
لماذا أغمي على والدي فجأة؟
I lost my mother when I was young.
لقد فقدت والدتي عندما كنت صغيرا.
My father brought me up.
لقد رباني والدي.
My father
والدي
is my only family in this world.
هي عائلتي الوحيدة في هذا العالم.
He's like
إنه مثل
my living faith.
ايماني الحي.
You probably understand
ربما تفهم
that feeling, right?
هذا الشعور، أليس كذلك؟
Ever since my father got sick,
منذ أن مرض والدي،
he's been hell-bent on me marrying Xubu Huai,
لقد كان عازمًا على أن أتزوج من Xubu Huai،
worried that I, a woman,
أشعر بالقلق لأنني امرأة،
would be swallowed up by those two gangs
سيتم ابتلاعها من قبل هاتين العصابتين
if anything happened to him.
إذا حدث له أي شيء.
It was as if
كان الأمر كما لو
he was handing over his most beloved treasure
لقد كان يسلم كنزه العزيز
to another who seemed
إلى آخر بدا
to be able to protect it,
لكي نتمكن من حمايته،
so he tried to keep me away.
لذلك حاول أن يبقيني بعيدًا.
Lord Wen
اللورد وين
is a good father.
هو أب جيد.
He is always protecting me,
إنه يحميني دائمًا
so I want to save him.
لذلك أريد أن أنقذه.
Fu Sheng.
فو شنغ.
If you can save my father,
إذا كنت تستطيع إنقاذ والدي،
I can give you great wealth or help you
أستطيع أن أعطيك ثروة عظيمة أو أساعدك
find the Treasure of the Sealed Book.
العثور على كنز الكتاب المختوم.
I can give you anything.
أستطيع أن أعطيك أي شيء.
I just want him to live.
أريد فقط أن يعيش.
But
لكن
I'm not sure now.
أنا لست متأكدة الآن.
Wen Jue.
ون جوي.
Today, I kneel down and beg you
اليوم أركع وأتوسل إليك
to save my father.
لإنقاذ والدي.
I am only what I am
أنا فقط ما أنا عليه
if he is alive.
إذا كان على قيد الحياة.
If he dies,
إذا مات،
I will have no one else
لن يكون لدي شخص آخر
in the world to hold on to.
في العالم للتمسك بها.
Fu Sheng.
فو شنغ.
Please.
لو سمحت.
Do what you can
افعل ما بوسعك
to save him.
لإنقاذه.
Get up.
استيقظ.
Come on.
تعال.
I would have done everything
كنت سأفعل كل شيء
even if you hadn't said so.
حتى لو لم تقل ذلك.
Siming.
سيمينغ.
Nice work.
عمل جميل.
Monkey.
قرد.
You're a great benefactor to me.
أنت فاعل خير عظيم بالنسبة لي.
Siming.
سيمينغ.
Why are you saluting this monkey?
لماذا تحيي هذا القرد؟
Li Zhizhuo tried to kill me again.
لقد حاول لي تشيزوو قتلي مرة أخرى.
Thanks to Young Mistress arriving in time
شكرًا للسيدة الشابة التي وصلت في الوقت المناسب
and saving my life.
وإنقاذ حياتي.
Didn't you say
ألم تقل؟
he wouldn't kill you again?
لن يقتلك مرة أخرى؟
Then if he wants to kill you,
ثم إذا أراد قتلك،
he can do this at any time.
يمكنه أن يفعل هذا في أي وقت.
We'd better go.
من الأفضل أن نذهب.
Go?
يذهب؟
It's an opportunity.
إنها فرصة.
Opportunity?
فرصة؟
How did he die?
كيف مات؟
This traitor thought
هذا الخائن فكر
he could rest easy
كان بإمكانه أن يرتاح بسهولة
in the haunted mansion,
في القصر المسكون،
but one of my carriage stewards
لكن أحد مشرفي عربتي
found him
وجدته
and killed him
وقتله
on the spot.
على الفور.
This man's name was Sun Siming,
اسم هذا الرجل كان سون سيمينغ،
and he was a man with a quick mind.
وكان رجلاً سريع البديهة.
My lord has ordered you
لقد أمرك سيدي
to purchase for him the blades
لشراء له الشفرات
to be auctioned at the Golden Bloom Banquet.
سيتم عرضها للبيع بالمزاد العلني في Golden Bloom Banquet.
But if the Jibei Chamber of Commerce
ولكن إذا كانت غرفة التجارة Jibei
calls for so much
يدعو إلى الكثير
to participate in the Golden Bloom Banquet,
للمشاركة في حفل Golden Bloom،
will it arouse
هل سوف يثير
the suspicion of other forces?
الشكوك حول قوى أخرى؟
This is your business.
هذا عملك .
Figure it out yourself.
اكتشف ذلك بنفسك.
Your head will leave your body
رأسك سيترك جسدك
if you screw this up.
إذا أفسدت هذا الأمر.
Get out of here.
اخرج من هنا.
I want to be alone for a while.
أريد أن أكون وحدي لفترة من الوقت.
Senior.
كبير.
I've lost the last of my family.
لقد فقدت آخر فرد من عائلتي.
Hurry up.
اسرع.
Why are you in such a hurry?
لماذا أنت في عجلة من أمرك؟
If you can't cure city lord,
إذا لم تتمكن من علاج سيد المدينة،
Wen Jiu will kill us.
وين جيو سوف يقتلنا.
How about this?
ماذا عن هذا؟
Now write a prescription.
الآن اكتب الوصفة الطبية.
It's the kind of prescription
إنه نوع من الوصفات الطبية
that will cure city lord.
هذا سوف يعالج سيد المدينة.
Then tell Wen Jue we're going out of town
ثم أخبر وين جو أننا سنخرج من المدينة
[Aloofness] to pick up some medicine.
[العزلة] لالتقاط بعض الأدوية.
Wen Jiu will certainly not stop us.
بالتأكيد لن يوقفنا وين جيو.
Once we leave the city gates,
بمجرد أن نغادر أبواب المدينة،
we'll ditch Wen Jue and run,
سوف نتخلى عن وين جوي ونهرب،
and never return to this hellhole.
ولا تعود أبدًا إلى هذا الجحيم.
No.
لا.
I've promised Wen Jue
لقد وعدت وين جو
I'd save her father.
سأنقذ والدها.
Why are you so stubborn?
لماذا أنت عنيد جداً؟
Why do you still care
لماذا لا تزال تهتم؟
about promises at this point?
حول الوعود في هذه المرحلة؟
A man's got to keep his word.
يجب على الرجل أن يفي بكلمته.
Besides, if Wen Yu dies,
وبالإضافة إلى ذلك، إذا مات وين يو،
Wen Jue will be an orphan, right?
وين جوي سيكون يتيمًا، أليس كذلك؟
Aren't you afraid
ألا تخاف؟
that if she becomes an orphan,
أنها إذا أصبحت يتيمة،
we'll both become ghosts?
هل سنصبح كلانا أشباحًا؟
Gu Tian.
قو تيان.
You have two younger brothers.
لديك شقيقان أصغر منك.
You'd better not get caught up
من الأفضل أن لا تنشغل
in this trouble.
في هذه المشكلة.
How about this?
ماذا عن هذا؟
I'll tell Wen Jiu
سأخبر وين جيو
that you can't help much with the cure,
أنك لا تستطيع المساعدة كثيرًا في العلاج،
but you have to go back home
ولكن عليك العودة إلى المنزل
because of a family matter.
بسبب مسألة عائلية.
You've arranged it plainly,
لقد رتبت الأمر بوضوح،
but I also have my creed.
ولكن لدي أيضًا عقيدتي.
I never
انا لم افعل ذلك ابدا
owe anyone.
لا أدين لأحد.
Well,
حسنًا،
I'll help you one last time
سأساعدك للمرة الأخيرة
before I go.
قبل أن أذهب.
Is there anything else you want to do?
هل هناك أي شيء آخر تريد القيام به؟
You really can't help
لا يمكنك المساعدة حقًا
with the treatment,
مع العلاج،
so just look up
لذا فقط انظر للأعلى
tussah silk for me.
حرير توساه بالنسبة لي.
Okay,
تمام،
but I'm afraid
ولكنني خائف
it involves Breakwall.
إنه يتضمن Breakwall.
It's too dangerous.
إنه أمر خطير للغاية.
That counts as two favors.
وهذا يعد بمثابة خدمتين.
In that case,
في هذه الحالة،
you owe me one.
أنت مدين لي بواحدة.
Give me a portion of the Treasure of the Sealed Book
أعطني جزءًا من كنز الكتاب المختوم
when you find it.
عندما تجده.
And if I die?
وإذا مت؟
Simple.
بسيط.
I get your
انا احصل عليك
Bird Jade Plate.
لوحة اليشم الطيور.
All right.
حسنًا.
So
لذا
don't die.
لا تموت
[Chunyun House]
[بيت تشونيون]
Regarding the tussah silk,
فيما يتعلق بالحرير التوساه،
I need to trouble you.
أريد أن أزعجك.
Don't worry, Mr. Gu.
لا تقلق يا سيد جو.
I'll go to Feng Qianli.
سأذهب إلى فنغ تشيانلي.
Still one day?
هل هناك يوم واحد؟
Yes.
نعم.
Mr. Gu, you're so powerful.
السيد جو، أنت قوي جدًا.
You've come to order my brother around.
لقد أتيت لتأمر أخي.
[Graceful and Attractive]
[رشيقة وجذابة]
I didn't want to bother you today.
لم أرد أن أزعجك اليوم.
But you came to my house anyway.
لكنك أتيت إلى منزلي على أية حال.
I'm leaving.
انا ذاهب.
I didn't want to be in such a hurry,
لم أكن أريد أن أكون في عجلة من أمري،
but since I came to Xichuan,
ولكن منذ أن أتيت إلى شيتشوان،
everything has gone wrong.
لقد أصبح كل شيء خاطئا.
Not only have I made no money,
لم أربح أي أموال فحسب،
but also I've gotten into trouble.
ولكنني أيضًا دخلت في مشكلة.
If I don't leave,
إذا لم أرحل،
I'm afraid I...
أخشى أنني...
You can leave if you want to.
يمكنك المغادرة إذا كنت تريد ذلك.
No need for words.
لا حاجة للكلمات.
I didn't understand
أنا لم أفهم
why I wanted to come
لماذا أردت أن آتي
into your room today.
إلى غرفتك اليوم.
It was only when I got to the door
فقط عندما وصلت إلى الباب
that I realized
أنني أدركت
I couldn't leave
لم أستطع المغادرة
without seeing you.
دون رؤيتك.
Now you've seen me.
لقد رأيتني الآن.
So
لذا
I am reluctant even more.
أنا متردد أكثر.
Get lost.
اغرب عن وجهي.
Yes, ma'am.
نعم سيدتي.
After thinking about it,
وبعد التفكير في الأمر،
I think what happened at Lin's Mansion
أعتقد أن ما حدث في قصر لين
is a big conspiracy.
هي مؤامرة كبيرة.
Li Zhizhuo tried
حاول Li Zhizhuo
to burn Lin's Mansion many times.
لحرق قصر لين عدة مرات.
Why does he keep holding on
لماذا يستمر في التمسك؟
to Lin's Mansion?
إلى قصر لين؟
He wants to force Master Lin to show up.
يريد إجبار السيد لين على الظهور.
But Master Lin
لكن السيد لين
is a traitor to Breakwall,
هو خائن لبريكاوول،
so is Li Zhizhuo also a member of Breakwall?
فهل لي تشيزوو عضو في Breakwall أيضًا؟
In that case,
في هذه الحالة،
Song Jingye and your father's deaths
سونغ جينغي ووفاة والدك
were the work of Breakwall
كان عمل بريكوال
in order to find the Bird Jade Plate
من أجل العثور على لوحة اليشم الطائر
and the Cloud-shaped Jade?
واليشم على شكل سحابة؟
But they didn't realize
لكنهم لم يدركوا
that Master Lin gave us
الذي أعطانا إياه السيد لين
the Cloud-shaped Jade to protect himself
اليشم على شكل سحابة لحماية نفسه
or that the Bird Jade Plate
أو أن لوحة اليشم الطيور
they wanted so badly
لقد أرادوا ذلك بشدة
was right in front of their eyes,
كان أمام أعينهم مباشرة،
but no one found it.
ولكن لم يجده أحد.
It was all just luck.
لقد كان كل هذا مجرد حظ.
The woman who appeared
المرأة التي ظهرت
in Lin's Mansion didn't kill us.
في قصر لين لم يقتلنا.
But since she appeared in Lin's Mansion,
ولكن منذ ظهورها في قصر لين،
she should have something
يجب أن يكون لديها شيء ما
to do with Breakwall.
تتعلق بـ Breakwall.
Moreover,
علاوة على ذلك،
I found
لقد وجدت
a horseshoe-shaped mark
علامة على شكل حدوة حصان
on her neck before I fainted.
على رقبتها قبل أن أغمى علي.
If we find this person,
إذا وجدنا هذا الشخص،
we will interrogate where the Sealed Book is located.
سوف نتساءل عن مكان وجود الكتاب المختوم.
At that time,
في ذلك الوقت،
will we be able to open
هل سنكون قادرين على فتح
the Treasure of the Sealed Book?
كنز الكتاب المختوم؟
Will the treasure
هل سيكون الكنز
be countless?
هل تكون لا تعد ولا تحصى؟
Yes, it will.
نعم سوف يحدث ذلك.
I heard you were having trouble with your eyes.
سمعت أنك تعاني من مشاكل في عينيك.
How do you feel now?
كيف تشعر الآن؟
Mr. Chairman.
السيد الرئيس.
What brings you here?
ما الذي أتى بك إلى هنا؟
They're good horses,
إنهم خيول جيدة
but
لكن
will they be still so good
هل سيظلون جيدين هكذا؟
if another owner keeps them?
إذا احتفظ بها مالك آخر؟
Mr. Chairman.
السيد الرئيس.
Have I done something
هل فعلت شيئا
to displease you?
لإزعاجك؟
We're all brothers,
نحن جميعا إخوة
so why do you make such a fuss?
فلماذا تثير كل هذه الضجة؟
How dare I be a brother
كيف أجرؤ على أن أكون أخًا
to Mr. Chairman?
إلى السيد الرئيس؟
I wouldn't dare.
لا أجرؤ على ذلك.
What's wrong with that?
ما الخطأ في ذلك؟
Didn't you hurt your eye
ألم تؤذي عينك؟
for the Jibei Chamber of Commerce?
لغرفة التجارة Jibei؟
How did Lin hurt you
كيف أذيتك لين؟
so badly?
سيئة للغاية؟
So did he
ففعل هو
press you for something
أضغط عليك من أجل شيء ما
or did he
أم أنه فعل
want you to do something for him?
هل تريد أن تفعل شيئا له؟
The old man was arrogant.
وكان الرجل العجوز متغطرسًا.
He despised me
لقد احتقرني
through and through.
من خلال ومن خلال.
My injuries didn't come out of Lin's Mansion.
إصاباتي لم تخرج من قصر لين.
They came out of nowhere.
لقد خرجوا من العدم.
My brother said I was possessed
قال أخي أنني كنت مسكونًا
and suggested I see a witch doctor.
وأقترح أن أرى طبيبًا ساحرًا.
Is that true?
هل هذا صحيح؟
Don't lie to me.
لا تكذب علي.
I have good intentions.
لدي نوايا حسنة.
If I tell you a lie,
إذا قلت لك كذبة،
I'll go blind in this eye.
سأصاب بالعمى في هذه العين.
Good.
جيد.
You have been smart
لقد كنت ذكيا
and done a great job for me,
وقد قام بعمل عظيم بالنسبة لي،
so I'll give you a great gift.
لذا سأقدم لك هدية عظيمة.
Be sure to accept it.
تأكد من قبوله.
What does Mr. Chairman want to give me?
ماذا يريد السيد الرئيس أن يقدم لي؟
Siming.
سيمينغ.
A beautiful woman is in your room.
هناك امرأة جميلة في غرفتك.
Come on.
تعال.
You have been smart
لقد كنت ذكيا
and done a great job for me,
وقد قام بعمل عظيم بالنسبة لي،
so I'll give you a great gift.
لذا سأقدم لك هدية عظيمة.
My brother.
أخي.
Come here.
تعال الى هنا.
Do you want a wife?
هل تريد زوجة؟
Yes, I do.
نعم أفعل.
Of course.
بالطبع.
Even in my dreams.
حتى في أحلامي.
The woman there
المرأة هناك
is the wife I give you.
هي الزوجة التي أعطيك إياها.
Really?
حقًا؟
So...
لذا...
Go.
يذهب.
Darling.
محبوب.
Who are you?
من أنت؟
- You're my wife. - Stay away.
-أنت زوجتي. - ابتعد.
Stay away.
ابقى بعيدا.
A perfect match.
مباراة مثالية.
Nice.
لطيف - جيد.
Everyone's looking for the Treasure of the Sealed Book.
الجميع يبحثون عن كنز الكتاب المختوم.
If it were me...
لو كنت أنا...
Where did you get it?
من أين حصلت عليه؟
Master Lin gave it to me before he died.
لقد أعطاني إياه السيد لين قبل أن يموت.
Ever since I took it,
منذ أن أخذته،
I've kept it in plain sight
لقد أبقيته في مرأى من الجميع
just so you could listen to me
فقط حتى تتمكن من الاستماع لي
when you came.
عندما أتيت.
What do you want to say?
ماذا تريد أن تقول؟
He died with a grievance,
لقد مات وهو مظلوم.
so he had something to say.
فكان لديه شيئا ليقوله.
With a grievance?
مع شكوى؟
You didn't kill him?
لم تقتله؟
He was a good fighter.
لقد كان مقاتلاً جيداً.
I, as a non-fighter,
أنا، كشخص غير مقاتل،
couldn't even get close to him.
لم أستطع حتى الاقتراب منه.
You still don't believe
مازلت لا تصدق
what I say,
ما أقوله
but before he died,
ولكن قبل أن يموت،
he told me
لقد قال لي
he had something else
كان لديه شيء آخر
that would make you believe me.
هذا سيجعلك تصدقني.
Before he died,
قبل أن يموت،
he asked me to tell you
لقد طلب مني أن أخبرك
to go as far away as possible
للذهاب إلى أبعد ما يمكن
from Li Zhizhuo.
من لي Zhizhuo.
He is no longer
انه لم يعد
with the organization.
مع المنظمة.
If you get too close to him,
إذا اقتربت منه كثيرًا،
he will hurt you.
سوف يؤذيك.
Why should I believe you?
لماذا يجب أن أصدقك؟
Li Zhizhuo said you killed him.
قال Li Zhizhuo أنك قتلته.
If you asked him, he must have said so.
إذا سألته، فلا بد أنه قال ذلك.
If you give me time,
إذا أعطيتني الوقت،
I'll prove it to you.
سأثبت لك ذلك.
OK.
نعم.
I believe you this time.
أنا أصدقك هذه المرة.
Take it.
خذها.
With it, you can find me anytime.
بواسطته يمكنك أن تجدني في أي وقت.
Yes, ma'am.
نعم سيدتي.
Siming.
سيمينغ.
It's probably a venom attack.
ربما يكون هجومًا بالسم.
What should I do?
ماذا علي أن أفعل؟
I'll go to the Chamber of Commerce.
سأذهب إلى غرفة التجارة.
Fu Sheng.
فو شنغ.
Go to Fu Sheng.
اذهب إلى فو شنغ.
Okay, Fu Sheng.
حسنًا، فو شنغ.
Let's go.
دعنا نذهب.
Be careful.
احرص.
Serious illnesses need strong medicine.
الأمراض الخطيرة تحتاج إلى دواء قوي.
If he wants to cure Wen Yu,
إذا أراد علاج وين يو،
he must use a powerful medicine
يجب عليه استخدام دواء قوي
to tonify him.
لتقويته.
When he becomes energetic,
عندما يصبح نشيطا،
he'll definitely not get sick.
لن يمرض بالتأكيد.
That will kill him.
هذا سوف يقتله.
Treatise on Febrile Diseases mentions
رسالة في الأمراض الحموية تذكر
that those who have retch,
أن أولئك الذين لديهم غثيان،
salivation,
اللعاب
and headaches
والصداع
should mainly drink fructus evodiae.
ينبغي شرب فاكهة إيفوديا بشكل أساسي.
He has had a lot of soup like that.
لقد تناول الكثير من الحساء مثل هذا.
I think he should
أعتقد أنه ينبغي عليه
soak ginseng in water
نقع الجينسنغ في الماء
and then have the city lord drink a bowl of that every two hours.
ثم اطلب من سيد المدينة أن يشرب وعاءً من هذا المشروب كل ساعتين.
Nonsense.
هراء.
What are you thinking?
ماذا تفكر؟
I'm wondering
انا اتساءل
if you guys fight
إذا تقاتلتم يا رفاق
when I'm not around.
عندما لا أكون موجودًا.
Oh, no.
أوه لا.
Crazy Fu is so crazy.
كريزي فو مجنون جدًا.
We're a figment of your imagination.
نحن مجرد خيالك
This house doesn't exist without you,
هذا البيت لا وجود له بدونك
and neither do we.
ونحن أيضا لا نفعل ذلك.
How could we fight?
كيف يمكننا القتال؟
You'd better figure out how to save Wen Yu.
من الأفضل أن تجد طريقة لإنقاذ وين يو.
Annoying.
مزعج.
My brother.
أخي.
Why did you push him?
لماذا دفعته؟
If he falls and gets hurt,
إذا سقط وأصيب،
who will treat me?
من سيعالجني؟
Help him up.
ساعده على النهوض.
Why did you push me?
لماذا دفعتني؟
Save him.
انقذه
Physician Fu.
الطبيب فو.
My arm is in pain.
ذراعي تؤلمني.
Please check it for me.
من فضلك تأكد من ذلك بالنسبة لي.
Is the snake venom acting up again?
هل سم الثعبان ينشط مرة أخرى؟
There's no swelling or ecchymosis.
لا يوجد تورم أو كدمة.
Move your arms and legs.
حرك ذراعيك وساقيك.
Your limbs also move normally.
وتتحرك أطرافك أيضًا بشكل طبيعي.
Stick out your tongue.
أخرج لسانك.
No poisoning
لا للتسمم
on your tongue or eyelids.
على لسانك أو جفونك.
Have you had any dizziness lately?
هل شعرت بالدوار في الآونة الأخيرة؟
No.
لا.
Then this is not snake venom.
إذن هذا ليس سم الثعبان.
But I can't lift my arm.
ولكنني لا أستطيع رفع ذراعي.
Come here.
تعال الى هنا.
I'll take your pulse.
سأقيس نبضك.
Your Excellency.
معالي الوزير.
Please take the medicine.
من فضلك خذ الدواء.
No.
لا.
What are you doing?
ماذا تفعل؟
Get up.
استيقظ.
I'll drink it.
سأشربه.
Let him in.
دعوه يدخل.
Yes, sir.
نعم سيدي.
Come in.
ادخل.
Lord Wen.
اللورد وين.
Feng Qianli, from Hearsay-capturing Pavilion,
فينج تشيانلي، من جناح التقاط الإشاعات،
has come to report.
لقد جاء للإبلاغ.
Fu Sheng and Gu Tian's resumes
السيرة الذاتية لـ فو شنغ وجو تيان
are all here.
كلهم هنا.
[The animals in the show are props]
[الحيوانات في العرض هي الدعائم]
[No animals were harmed during the filming]
[لم يتم إيذاء أي حيوان أثناء التصوير]
♪Under the sky, light and shadow go together♪
♪تحت السماء، الضوء والظل يذهبان معًا♪
♪The reflection of prosperity and splendor♪
♪انعكاس الرخاء والروعة♪
♪Hides many secrets♪
♪يخفي العديد من الأسرار♪
♪It's like♪
♪إنه مثل♪
♪Every page of your life♪
♪كل صفحة من حياتك♪
♪It's all about destiny♪
♪الأمر كله يتعلق بالقدر♪
♪The story has tragedy and comedy♪
♪القصة تحتوي على مأساة وكوميديا ​​♪
♪To discover the mystery♪
♪لاكتشاف اللغز♪
♪We go on adventures♪
♪نحن نذهب في مغامرات♪
♪We don't run away or compromise easily♪
♪نحن لا نهرب أو نتنازل بسهولة♪
♪When dawn comes♪
♪عندما يأتي الفجر♪
♪The light shines♪
♪النور يضيء♪
♪We follow the path of discovery♪
♪نحن نتبع طريق الاكتشاف♪
♪To chase and welcome♪
♪ للمطاردة والترحيب ♪
♪Every unknown story♪
♪كل قصة غير معروفة♪
♪We take a trip together♪
♪نحن نقوم برحلة معًا♪
♪With hot blood and original purpose♪
♪مع الدم الساخن والغرض الأصلي♪
♪We seize the day and live it to the fullest♪
♪نحن نستغل اليوم ونعيشه على أكمل وجه♪
♪Leave a mark on our journey♪
♪اترك علامة في رحلتنا♪
♪Scatter the darkness with our hearts♪
♪نبدد الظلام بقلوبنا♪
♪Aspire to make a difference♪
♪أطمح إلى إحداث فرق♪
♪To discover the mystery♪
♪لاكتشاف اللغز♪
♪We go on adventures♪
♪نحن نذهب في مغامرات♪
♪We don't run away or compromise easily♪
♪نحن لا نهرب أو نتنازل بسهولة♪
♪When dawn comes♪
♪عندما يأتي الفجر♪
♪The light shines♪
♪النور يضيء♪
♪We follow the path of discovery♪
♪نحن نتبع طريق الاكتشاف♪
♪To chase and welcome♪
♪ للمطاردة والترحيب ♪
♪Every unknown story♪
♪كل قصة غير معروفة♪
♪We take a trip together♪
♪نحن نقوم برحلة معًا♪
♪With hot blood and original purpose♪
♪مع الدم الساخن والغرض الأصلي♪
♪We seize the day and live it to the fullest♪
♪نحن نستغل اليوم ونعيشه على أكمل وجه♪
♪Leave a mark on our journey♪
♪اترك علامة في رحلتنا♪
♪Scatter the darkness with our hearts♪
♪نبدد الظلام بقلوبنا♪
♪Aspire to make a difference♪
♪أطمح إلى إحداث فرق♪
♪Make a difference♪
♪أحدث فرقًا♪
♪We take a trip together♪
♪نحن نقوم برحلة معًا♪
♪Through hardships♪
♪من خلال الصعوبات♪
♪We will find the glory♪
♪سوف نجد المجد♪
♪Aspire to make a difference♪
♪أطمح إلى إحداث فرق♪